<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marco Paga</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/</link><description>Recent content on Marco Paga</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 08:17:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marco-paga.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/about-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/about-me/</guid><description>Here you can find a short information about my current skill set.
Skills proven in professional projects Topic Item Focus Software Architecture, IT Infrastructure and Automation Workshops Requirements Workshopss, Technical Workshops, Architecture Reviews, Assessments CI/CD Gitlab Pipelines, Github Actions, Azure DevOps, Tekton, Jenkins Platforms Containers, Kubernetes, AWS, Azure, Google Cloud, on-prem Solutions Server Tomcat, Jetty, Nginx, Traefik, Apache Modelling UML, BPMN, OpenAPI and more Tool-specific Notations Languages Java/Kotlin Spring Ecosystem, TypeScript with NestJS, Angular and React, Python, HTML Persistence Oracle SQL with PL/SQL, DynamoDB, Streaming Architectures with e.</description></item><item><title>Gitops</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/gitops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 08:17:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/gitops/</guid><description>Table of contents: Was ist GitOps? Warum? Was war nochmal Infastructure as Code? GitOps Flux CD Flux Version 2 Komponenten Konzepte „Hello, World!“ Fazit und Ausblick Was ist GitOps? GitOps betrachtet den Auslieferungsprozess von Software auf den verschiedenen Stages von einer Entwicklungsumgebung bis hin zu einer produktiven Umgebung. Wie der Name schon vermuten lässt, wird git als Versionskontrollsystem verwendet und bildet damit die revisionssichere Historie ab. Alle Änderungen werden über diesen nachvollziehbaren Weg in eine Umgebung gebracht.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Acceleration Framework</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/products/devops-acceleration-framework/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 08:45:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/products/devops-acceleration-framework/</guid><description>Overview Motivation &amp;ldquo;We are too slow! The competitors are running ahead of us. What can we do to be faster?&amp;rdquo; Anyone who is familiar with these questions knows how difficult they are to answer. You focus on the teams and processes involved and you can&amp;rsquo; t find the problem.
If this sounds familiar, I can help you with the DevOps Acceleration Framework. The framework offers you a proven path from inventory to solution finding embedded in a transparent process.</description></item><item><title>Tekton Triggers CEL</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/tekton-triggers-cel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 14:49:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/tekton-triggers-cel/</guid><description>or how to convert a git ref to a branch name
Tekton Triggers is a Tekton project which allows to receive webhooks and react appropriately to those. You can follow along my article on the codecentric blog to see what is possible.
Tekton triggers includes a conecpt which is called Interceptors that provide a way to implement cross cutting concerns. To give you a quick example: If you integrate Github with Tekton you hopefully want to validate if your project is calling the tekton installation since you don&amp;rsquo;t want anybody stumbling on your tekton installation to run pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Github Actions test a full Tekton CI installation</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/github-actions-testen-tekton-ci/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/github-actions-testen-tekton-ci/</guid><description>Table of contents: Tekton Cloud Native CI/CD A boiled down CI Pipeline Interacting with tekton GitHub Actions Demo Project The Testing Recap In software development, it is good practice to write tests for the productive code. We see the value in our daily work in many places when it comes to further developing the software. But CI - systems, although they make the safety net possible for whole teams in the first place, are often far from the principle.</description></item><item><title>Impressum</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/impressum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 10:39:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/impressum/</guid><description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG Marco Paga
Graf-Recke-ѕtr. 5
40239 Düsseldorf
Kontakt E-Mail: marco.paga@gmail.com
Verantwortlich für den Inhalt nach § 55 Abs. 2 RStV: Marco Paga
Graf-Recke-ѕtr. 5
40239 Düsseldorf
Haftung fuer Inhalte Die Inhalte dieser Seiten wurden mit größter Sorgfalt erstellt. Für die Richtigkeit, Vollständigkeit und Aktualität der Inhalte kann ich jedoch keine Gewähr übernehmen. Als Diensteanbieter bin ich gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich.</description></item><item><title>Articles</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/articles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 14:58:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/articles/</guid><description>18.05.2022 Artikel im Softwerker Vol. 20
29.04.2022 Github Actions test a full Tekton CI installation
04.03.2022 Tekton Triggers in der Praxis
Tekton Triggers in practice
11.02.2022 Tekton Buildpack Pipeline: Alles schon da?
Standing on the shoulders of the Tekton community: Tekton buildpack pipeline
19.01.2022 Tekton Cloud-native CI/CD – a pragmatic intro
Tekton Cloud-Native CI/CD: Ein pragmatisches Intro
01.2022 Artikel im Softwerker 19
2019 Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt wildcard TLS certificates on Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</description></item></channel></rss>