<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Entries on Marco Paga</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/</link><description>Recent content in Entries on Marco Paga</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 08:17:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marco-paga.eu/entries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gitops</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/gitops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 08:17:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/gitops/</guid><description>Table of contents: Was ist GitOps? Warum? Was war nochmal Infastructure as Code? GitOps Flux CD Flux Version 2 Komponenten Konzepte „Hello, World!“ Fazit und Ausblick Was ist GitOps? GitOps betrachtet den Auslieferungsprozess von Software auf den verschiedenen Stages von einer Entwicklungsumgebung bis hin zu einer produktiven Umgebung. Wie der Name schon vermuten lässt, wird git als Versionskontrollsystem verwendet und bildet damit die revisionssichere Historie ab. Alle Änderungen werden über diesen nachvollziehbaren Weg in eine Umgebung gebracht.</description></item><item><title>Tekton Triggers CEL</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/tekton-triggers-cel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 14:49:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/tekton-triggers-cel/</guid><description>or how to convert a git ref to a branch name
Tekton Triggers is a Tekton project which allows to receive webhooks and react appropriately to those. You can follow along my article on the codecentric blog to see what is possible.
Tekton triggers includes a conecpt which is called Interceptors that provide a way to implement cross cutting concerns. To give you a quick example: If you integrate Github with Tekton you hopefully want to validate if your project is calling the tekton installation since you don&amp;rsquo;t want anybody stumbling on your tekton installation to run pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Github Actions test a full Tekton CI installation</title><link>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/github-actions-testen-tekton-ci/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://marco-paga.eu/entries/github-actions-testen-tekton-ci/</guid><description>Table of contents: Tekton Cloud Native CI/CD A boiled down CI Pipeline Interacting with tekton GitHub Actions Demo Project The Testing Recap In software development, it is good practice to write tests for the productive code. We see the value in our daily work in many places when it comes to further developing the software. But CI - systems, although they make the safety net possible for whole teams in the first place, are often far from the principle.</description></item></channel></rss>